CODY GRIFFITH

Santa Cruz, CA 669-204-6374 cody.griffith94@gmail.com
mathnstein.github.io



Mathematical Research Scientist

Summary

After about a decade of honing my applied mathematics I have developed the tools, experience and programming knowledge to make myself useful to any field of analysis. I am a research scientist in mass spectrometry where I specialize in developing algorithms for internal use as well as for customergrade products. My hope is to continue to broaden my skill set and work towards making a positive impact both at the industry/research level but also towards social good.

Education

2016 - 2018 M.Sc in Applied Mathematics

University of British Columbia

2012 - 2016 B.Sc in Applied Mathematics

Metropolitan State University of Denver

Work experience

December 2018 -Current Research Scientist

908 Devices

New to the realm of mass spectrometry, I quickly learned how to build efficient algorithms for the data-rich orbit-trap mass spectrometers. I soon was tasked with anticipating potential customer use cases and participated in UI/UX design for analysis software. While building new products, I was also in charge of maintaining current device platforms and functionality while bringing new features into software updates. Along with maintenance, I gave expert analysis for in-field device data reachback. All of this together taught me important facets of business development on top of algorithm design.

May 2018 - October 2018

Research Scientist

Data Science for Social Good (UBC)

As a means of applying my skills that would have a maximal impact on my community, I took part in a data science initiative to help the nearby city of Surrey understand the pitfalls in addressing childhood vulnerabilities. This project lasted a summer and led to unique collaboration with Microsoft Vancouver and culminated in a paper and a platform to combine city data, public census data, and the unique Early Childhood Instrument (EDI). This platform has been since utilized by Surrey and there is a follow-up project underway to expand on our findings.

Sept. 2016 - May 2018

Research/Teaching Assistant

University of British Columbia

As part of my training at the Master's level, I continued developing my teaching skills while taking on grading duties, leading in class activities and proctoring exams as a teaching assistant. But as a research assistant, I learned how mathematical research was done and further developed my ability to communicate high level ideas. I had gained insight into a various selection of methods and developed new approaches and methods in my research area.

Jan. 2015 - Aug. 2016

Lead/Private Tutor

Metropolitan University

To facilitate my growth in mathematics, I started tutoring. Overtime I had become the lead tutor in my universities tutor lab, a tutor in a mathematics specific lab and even a private tutor. As a lead, I trained and guided new tutors in their respective fields. As a private tutor, I was getting recommended from all labs I had worked with and soon had too many clients. I could teach any math course taught at my university as I had taken nearly every course offered.

Projects

- Formed the basis of analysis on a two-dimensional dynamical system with strange bifurcating behavior.
- Partnered with Data Science for Social Good to create a central database and platform to analyze this to explain childhood vulnerability in the city of Surrey.
- Used Spatial & Temporal Analysis to help Groundwork Denver to model E-Coli trends in a local river.
- Placed meritorious winner in 2016's Mathematical Competition in Modeling (MCM).
- Presented at JMM 2016 on computational and theoretical extensions to topics in Linear Algebra.
- Established a sequence of independent studies to develop a personalized and interest driven track: Functional Analysis, Discrete Wavelet Transformations, Advanced Linear Algebra, and Measure Theory.
- Developed a method of analysis on a Dual-Capacity Stochastic Queue. Then, presented this work at the 2015 MAA regional conference in Colorado Springs as well as at the Undergraduate Research Conference in Denver.

Skills

- Extensive programming with Mathematica, R, Matlab, Python and Julia
- Intensive critical thinking and problem solving honed along with Mathematics
- Ability to manage projects and experience leading a team
- Significant use of document preparation in Latex, Markdown, Overleaf and Microsoft office
- Familiar with slide preparation via Latex (beamer) or Powerpoint
- Well versed in source control and project work (Dropbox, Github, Subversion)
- Experience with the Cloud Network and other online data storage

Referees

Dr. Rachel Kuske Rachel@math.gatech.edu

Dr. Elizabeth Ribble emcclel3@msudenver.edu

Dr. Chris Harder Harderc@msudenver.edu

Dr. Robert Green bgreen@908devices.com

Chair of Mathematics Georgia Technical University

Chair of Mathematics MSU Denver

Professor of Mathematics MSU Denver

Algorithms Lead 908 Devices

Master's thesis supervisor.

Advising professor for my data science projects.

Advising professor in mathematical research. Direct boss at 908 Devices.